A Guide to the Records of the Communications Office of Governor Lawrence Douglas Wilder, 1989-1994 (bulk 1990-1993).
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Communications Office Records of Governor Lawrence Douglas Wilder,
1989-1994 (bulk 1990-1993).
The Library of Virginia
35539, 35581, 35586
Virginia. Govenor (1990-1994: Wilder).
37.05 cu. ft. (64 boxes)
Administrative Information
Arranged by series.
Access Restrictions
There are no access restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Accession 35539 was transferred by Lawrence Douglas Wilder, October 31, 1996.
Accession 35581 was transferred by Lawrence Douglas Wilder, October 21, 1997.
Accession 35586 was transferred by Lawrence Douglas Wilder, November 5, 1997
Historical Information
Lawrence Douglas Wilder was born in Richmond, Va., on January 17, 1931. He graduated from Virginia Union University in 1951 and afterwards was drafted into the Army, where he served in the Korean War from 1952-1953 and received a bronze star. He then attended the Howard University School of Law and graduated in 1959. Douglas Wilder was elected to the Virginia Senate in 1969 as the first African American member since Reconstruction and served in the Senate for five terms. In 1985, he was elected to the office of Lieutenant Governor as the first African American to be elected to statewide office in Virginia. L. Douglas Wilder won the election for Governor of Virginia in 1989 and served from January 13, 1990 to January 14, 1994. He was the first African American to be elected as Governor in United States.
The Office of Communications was responsible for all media relations and announcements. Duties included drafting press releases, responding to press inquiries, compiling daily news summaries, preparing certificates of recognition, releasing the Governor's public schedule, writing speeches, compiling briefings for press conferences and interviews, and working with the National Governors Association. In December 1989, Governor L. Douglas Wilder selected Laura Dillard to serve as Director of Communications. Dillard had formerly served as Governor Wilder's campaign press secretary. She resigned in August 1991, along with her Deputy Dirctor of Communications, Michelle Prosser. After her departure, Glenn Davidson was named Director of Communications. Davidson had previously served as the the Director of the Virginia Liaison Office.
Scope and Content
Communications Office records, 1989-1994, are housed in 64 boxes and are arranged by series. These records document the activities of the Communications Office during the administration of Governor Lawrence Douglas Wilder and include director's correspondence and subject files, Governor's public schedule, media advisories / press releases, newspaper clippings / news summaries, publications featuring Governor Wilder, and trade mission briefing binders.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into the following series:
Series I. Director's Correspondence and Subject Files, 1990-1994
Series II. Media Advisories, 1989-1994
Series III. Governor's Public Schedule, 1990-1993
Series IV. Media Packets, 1991-1992
Series V. Trade Mission Briefing Binders, 1991
Series VI. Newspaper articles about Governor Wilder, 1990-1993
Series VII. Publications featuring Governor Wilder, 1990-1993
Series VIII. Newspaper clippings by Subject, 1989-1991
Series IX. News Summaries, 1990-1994
Contents List
- Series I. Communication Director's correspondence and subject files, 1990-1994 Jan (Acc. 35539)., Extent: 5.95 cubic feet (17 boxes). (Box 25-41)
  Communication Director's correspondence and subject files, 1990-1994, are housed in 17 boxes and are arranged alphabetically, within each chronological subseries. Subseries are designated for correspondence and subject files of Laura Dillard, 1990-1991 Aug (Subseries A) and correspondence and subject files of Glenn Davidson, 1991-1994 (Subseries B). Correspondence and subject files include incoming and outgoing correspondence and topical files that may include agendas, brochures, conference materials, news clippings, news releases, newsletters, procedures, promotional materials, public service announcement scripts, and reports. This series includes inauguration planning records, State of the Commonwealth address planning records, and media requests forms for interviews.
  - Subseries A. Correspondence and subject files of Laura Dillard, 1990-1991.
    - Correspondence, 1990. (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, 1991 Jan-Aug. (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - Air and Space Museum, 1990. (Box 25, Folder 3)
    - Budget (Federal), 1990. (Box 25, Folder 4)
    - Cabinet Agenda (State of the Commonwealth Address), 1991. (Box 25, Folder 5)
    - CBS Education Conference, 1990. (Box 25, Folder 6)
    - Center for Innovative Technology, 1990. (Box 25, Folder 7)
    - Commonwealth, Secretary of the, 1990. (Box 25, Folder 8)
    - Drug Abuse and Resistance Education (DARE) funding, 1990. (Box 25, Folder 9)
    - Drug Education, 1990. (Box 25, Folder 10)
    - Drug Forfeiture Amendment, 1990. (Box 25, Folder 11)
    - Drug Initiatives, undated. (Box 25, Folder 12)
    - Drugs, Virginia Summit on, 1990. (Box 25, Folder 13)
    - Flag lowering, 1991. (Box 26, Folder 1)
    - Freedom of Information, 1990. (Box 26, Folder 2)
    - Governor's Fellows, 1990. (Box 26, Folder 3)
    - Governor's Forum, 1990-1991. (Box 26, Folder 4)
    - Governor's Report on Education, 1990. (Box 26, Folder 5)
    - Health and Human Resources, 1990. (Box 26, Folder 6)
    - Inauguration, 1990. (Box 26, Folder 7)
    - Judicial vacancies, 1990. (Box 26, Folder 8)
    - Liaison Office, Virginia, 1990. (Box 26, Folder 9)
    - Media requests, 1990 Jan-Mar. (Box 26, Folder 10)
    - Media requests, 1990 Apr-July. (Box 26, Folder 11)
    - Media requests, 1990 Aug-Sept. (Box 26, Folder 12)
    - Media requests, 1990 Oct-Dec. (Box 27, Folder 1)
    - Media requests, 1991 Jan-May. (Box 27, Folder 2)
    - Media requests, 1991 June-July. (Box 27, Folder 3)
    - Minority Business in Virginia, 1990. (Box 27, Folder 4)
    - Miscellaneous, 1990. (Box 27, Folder 5)
    - Model General Assembly, 1990-1991. (Box 27, Folder 6)
    - National Governors Association, 1990-1991. (Box 27, Folder 7)
    - Oil Crisis, 1990. (Box 27, Folder 8)
    - Photography, 1990. (Box 27, Folder 9)
    - Procedures, 1990. (Box 27, Folder 10)
    - Public Service Announcements, 1990-1991. (Box 27, Folder 11)
    - RF and P, 1990-1991. (Box 27, Folder 12)
    - Southern Governors' Association, 1990. (Box 27, Folder 13)
    - Speech index, 1991 Aug. (Box 28, Folder 1)
    - Speeches - Correspondence, 1990. (Box 28, Folder 2)
    - Speeches - Remarks, 1990 Aug 1. (Box 28, Folder 3)
    - Speeches - State of the Commonwealth Address, 1990 Jan 15. (Box 28, Folder 4)
    - Virginia Broadcasting Week (Public Service Announcement), 1990. (Box 28, Folder 5)
  - Subseries B. Correspondence and subject files of Glenn Davidson, 1991-1994.
    - Correspondence, 1991. (Box 29, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, 1992 Jan-Aug. (Box 29, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, 1992 Sept-Dec. (Box 29, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, 1993 Jan-Feb. (Box 29, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence, 1993 Mar. (Box 29, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence, 1993 Apr-May. (Box 29, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence, 1993 June-July. (Box 29, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence, 1993 Aug. (Box 29, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence, 1993 Sept-Oct. (Box 29, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence, 1993 Nov-Dec. (Box 29, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence, 1993. (Box 30, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, 1994. (Box 30, Folder 2)
    - Accounts, Dept. of - Statewide Financial Management and Compliance Quarterly Report, 1993. (Box 30, Folder 3)
    - Administration, Secretary of, 1991-1993. (Box 30, Folder 4)
    - African Trade Mission, 1993. (Box 30, Folder 5)
    - Aging, Dept. for the, 1991-1993. (Box 30, Folder 6)
    - Agriculture, Dept. of, 1991. (Box 30, Folder 7)
    - Air and Space Museum, National (Smithsonian), 1990-1993. (Box 30, Folder 8)
    - Air Pollution Control Board, 1991. (Box 30, Folder 9)
    - Alcoholic Beverage Control, Dept. of, 1991-1993. (Box 30, Folder 10)
    - AQUOLA - Association for the Quality of Life in America, 1992. (Box 30, Folder 11)
    - Article index, 1990-1992. (Box 30, Folder 12)
    - Ashe, Arthur, 1993. (Box 30, Folder 3)
    - Asian Trade Mission, 1993. (Box 31, Folder 1)
    - Aviation, Dept. of, 1993. (Box 31, Folder 2)
    - Base closures, 1993. (Box 31, Folder 3)
    - Bibiliography, 1992. (Box 31, Folder 4)
    - Biographical information for Gov. L. Douglas Wilder, 1990-1993. (Box 31, Folder 5)
    - Biographical information for Gov. L. Douglas Wilder - Articles, 1990-1993. (Box 31, Folder 6)
    - Biography requests, 1992-1993. (Box 31, Folder 7)
    - Bonds - General obligation, 1992. (Box 31, Folder 8)
    - Bonds - General obligation, 1992-1993. (Box 31, Folder 9)
    - Cassette tape index, undated. (Box 32, Folder 1)
    - CBS - Sixty Minutes, 1992. (Box 32, Folder 2)
    - Central American - Southern States Partnership - Delegates, 1991. (Box 32, Folder 3)
    - Central American Trade Mission, 1993. (Box 32, Folder 4)
    - Cheatham Annex, 1991. (Box 32, Folder 5)
    - Child Day Care and Early Childhood Programs, Council on, 1991. (Box 32, Folder 6)
    - Children, Dept. for, 1991. (Box 32, Folder 7)
    - Coal Miner pensions, 1991-1992. (Box 32, Folder 8)
    - Commonwealth, Secretary of the, 1993. (Box 32, Folder 9)
    - Conservation and Recreation, Dept. of, 1991. (Box 32, Folder 10)
    - Corrections, Dept. of - Prison costs, 1993. (Box 32, Folder 11)
    - Crime Initiatives (Violent), 1992-1993. (Box 32, Folder 12)
    - CSX-RFP Merger, 1992. (Box 32, Folder 13)
    - Defense Conversion, 1993. (Box 32, Folder 14)
    - Defense Conversion, Governor's Conference on, 1993. (Box 32, Folder 15)
    - Defense Conversion, Report of the Governor's Conference on, 1993. (Box 32, Folder 16)
    - Desert Storm, 1991. (Box 32, Folder 17)
    - Divestiture - Preliminary Report on South African Divestiture, 1991 Jan. (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - Divestiture - Progress Report on South African Divestiture, 1991 Dec. (Box 33, Folder 2)
    - Divestment, 1990-1991. (Box 33, Folder 3)
    - Drugs - Non-prescription, 1991. (Box 33, Folder 4)
    - Dulles Airport, 1992-1993. (Box 33, Folder 5)
    - Economic Development Commission, 1992-1993. (Box 33, Folder 6)
    - Economic Development, Dept. of, 1993. (Box 33, Folder 7)
    - Economic Development, Secretary of, 1992-1993. (Box 33, Folder 8)
    - Economic Development, Secretary of - Southwestern Virginia, 1991. (Box 33, Folder 9)
    - Education, Secretary of, 1991-1993. (Box 33, Folder 10)
    - Emergency Services, Dept. of, 1993. (Box 33, Folder 11)
    - Emergency Services, Dept. of - A Governor's Guide to Emergency Management (NGA), 1991. (Box 33, Folder 12)
    - Emergency Plan, 1992. (Box 33, Folder 13)
    - Environment, Council on the, 1991. (Box 34, Folder 1)
    - Environmental Quality, Dept. of, 1993. (Box 34, Folder 2)
    - Ethics Commission, 1992-1993. (Box 34, Folder 3)
    - Executions, 1993. (Box 34, Folder 4)
    - Finance, Secretary of, 1991-1993. (Box 34, Folder 5)
    - Financial World Magazine, 1992-1993. (Box 34, Folder 6)
    - Game and Inland Fisheries, Dept. of, 1992-1993. (Box 34, Folder 7)
    - General Assembly, 1993. (Box 34, Folder 8)
    - Gun Control, 1993. (Box 34, Folder 9)
    - Health, Dept. of, 1991. (Box 34, Folder 10)
    - Health, Dept. of, 1992. (Box 34, Folder 11)
    - Health, Dept. of, 1993-1994. (Box 34, Folder 12)
    - Health and Human Resources, Secretary of, 1991-1993. (Box 35, Folder 1)
    - Health Care Summit, 1992-1993. (Box 35, Folder 2)
    - Health Professions, Dept. of, 1991-1993. (Box 35, Folder 3)
    - Honduras, 1993. (Box 35, Folder 4)
    - Industrial Development Authority of Halifax County, 1993. (Box 35, Folder 5)
    - Interns, 1993. (Box 35, Folder 6)
    - Interview notes, 1991-1993. (Box 35, Folder 7)
    - Interview requests, 1993. (Box 35, Folder 8)
    - Labor and Industry, Dept. of, 1992-1993. (Box 35, Folder 9)
    - LaborFest, 1990. (Box 35, Folder 10)
    - Liaison Office, Virginia, 1991-1993. (Box 35, Folder 11)
    - Mansion and Capitol Square Events, 1991-1993. (Box 36, Folder 1)
    - Mansiona and Capitol Square Events - Press Corps Receptions, 1992-1993. (Box 36, Folder 2)
    - Marine Resources Commission, 1991-1993. (Box 36, Folder 3)
    - Medical Assistance Services, Dept. of, 1993. (Box 36, Folder 4)
    - Memoranda - Miscellaneous, 1992-1993. (Box 36, Folder 5)
    - Mental Health, Mental Retardation and Substance Abuse Services, Dept. of, 1991. (Box 36, Folder 6)
    - Mental Health, Mental Retardation and Substance Abuse Services, Dept. of, 1992-1993. (Box 36, Folder 7)
    - Messages from the Governor, 1990; 1992-1993. (Box 36, Folder 8)
    - Mines, Minerals and Energy, Dept. of, 1991-1992. (Box 36, Folder 9)
    - Mines, Minerals and Energy, Dept. of, 1993. (Box 37, Folder 1)
    - Minority Business Enterprise, Dept. of, 1993. (Box 37, Folder 2)
    - Miscellaneous, 1992. (Box 37, Folder 3)
    - Motor Vehicles, Dept. of (DMV), 1991-1992. (Box 37, Folder 4)
    - Museum of Fine Arts (VMFA), 1993. (Box 37, Folder 5)
    - National Guard, undated. (Box 37, Folder 6)
    - National Youth Sports Program, 1993. (Box 37, Folder 7)
    - Natural Resources, Secretary of, 1991-1993. (Box 37, Folder 8)
    - News clippings, 1991-1993. (Box 37, Folder 9)
    - Norplant, 1993. (Box 37, Folder 10)
    - Open Houses, 1990-1993. (Box 37, Folder 11)
    - Pacific Rim, 1993. (Box 37, Folder 12)
    - Permissions, 1993. (Box 37, Folder 13)
    - Personnel and Training, Dept. of, 1993. (Box 37, Folder 14)
    - Photo opportunity call around list, undated. (Box 37, Folder 15)
    - PPB, 1991-1993. (Box 38, Folder 1)
    - Press Corps, 1991-1993. (Box 38, Folder 2)
    - Press lists, 1990-1993. (Box 38, Folder 3)
    - Public Affairs Association, 1991-1993. (Box 38, Folder 4)
    - Public Safety, Secretary of, 1992-1993. (Box 38, Folder 5)
    - Public Safety, Secretary of - Task Force on Assault Firearms, 1993. (Box 38, Folder 6)
    - Public Safety Media Council, Central Virginia, 1991. (Box 38, Folder 7)
    - Public Service Announcements, 1990-1992. (Box 38, Folder 8)
    - Public Service Announcements, 1993. (Box 38, Folder 9)
    - Racing Commission, 1992-1993. (Box 38, Folder 10)
    - Rehabilitative Services, Dept. of, 1991-1993. (Box 38, Folder 11)
    - Savings Bonds, 1991. (Box 38, Folder 12)
    - Shared Provider, 1992. (Box 38, Folder 13)
    - Social Services, Dept. of, 1991-1993. (Box 39, Folder 1)
    - Southern Governors' Association, 1993. (Box 39, Folder 2)
    - Speeches (Exerpts), 1990-1993. (Box 39, Folder 3)
    - State of the Commonwealth Address - Planning, 1993. (Box 39, Folder 4)
    - State of the Commonwealth Address - Planning, 1993. (Box 39, Folder 5)
    - State of the Commonwealth Address - Planning, 1993. (Box 39, Folder 6)
    - State of the Commonwealth Address - Planning, 1993. (Box 39, Folder 7)
    - State Water Control Board, 1991. (Box 40, Folder 1)
    - Statement of Economic Interest, 1992. (Box 40, Folder 2)
    - Subject file index, undated. (Box 40, Folder 3)
    - Taxation, Dept. of, 1991-1993. (Box 40, Folder 4)
    - Thank you letters, 1992. (Box 40, Folder 5)
    - Thank you letters, 1993. (Box 40, Folder 6)
    - Thank you letters, 1993. (Box 40, Folder 7)
    - Three Years of Change, 1993. (Box 40, Folder 8)
    - Transportation, Dept. of, 1991-1993. (Box 40, Folder 9)
    - Transportation Testimony - U.S. House of Representatives, 1990. (Box 40, Folder 10)
    - Treasury, Dept. of, 1992. (Box 40, Folder 11)
    - Urban Commission, 1993. (Box 40, Folder 12)
    - Veterans Affairs, Dept. of, 1993. (Box 41, Folder 1)
    - Video index, 1990-1993. (Box 41, Folder 2)
    - Violent Crime legislation - Bill signing, 1993. (Box 41, Folder 3)
    - Virginia Alcohol Safety Action Program, 1991. (Box 41, Folder 4)
    - Virginia Education Loan Authority, 1992-1993. (Box 41, Folder 5)
    - Virginia Military Institute, 1993. (Box 41, Folder 6)
    - Virginia Municipal League, 1992. (Box 41, Folder 7)
    - Virginia Retirement System, 1990-1992. (Box 41, Folder 8)
    - Virginia Retirement System, 1991-1992. (Box 41, Folder 9)
    - Volunteerism, Dept. of, 1991. (Box 41, Folder 10)
    - Washington Airports Task Force, 1992-1993. (Box 41, Folder 11)
    - Washington, U.S.S. George - Commissioning, 199. (Box 41, Folder 12)
    - Wilder Library, 1993. (Box 41, Folder 13)
    - Youth and Family Services, Dept. of, 1991-1993. (Box 41, Folder 14)
- Series II. Media advisories, 1989-1994 Jan (Acc. 35539)., Extent: 2.1 cubic feet (6 boxes). (Box 42-47)
  Media advisories, 1989-1994, are housed in 6 boxes and are arranged chronologically. These press releases alert the media to administration announcements and initiatives, including appointments and resignations; bill signings; proclamations; information on clemency, pardons and executions; recognition of important events;, economic development announcements; and the Governor's public appearances, speaking engagements, or interviews.
  - Media advisories, 1989 Nov-Dec. (Box 42, Folder 1)
  - Media advisories, 1990 Jan. (Box 42, Folder 2)
  - Media advisories, 1990 Feb. (Box 42, Folder 3)
  - Media advisories, 1990 Mar. (Box 42, Folder 4)
  - Media advisories, 1990 Apr. (Box 42, Folder 5)
  - Media advisories, 1990 May. (Box 42, Folder 6)
  - Media advisories, 1990 June. (Box 42, Folder 7)
  - Media advisories, 1990 July. (Box 42, Folder 8)
  - Media advisories, 1990 Aug. (Box 42, Folder 9)
  - Media advisories, 1990 Sept. (Box 43, Folder 1)
  - Media advisories, 1990 Oct. (Box 43, Folder 2)
  - Media advisories, 1990 Nov. (Box 43, Folder 3)
  - Media advisories, 1990 Dec. (Box 43, Folder 4)
  - Media advisories, 1991 Jan. (Box 43, Folder 5)
  - Media advisories, 1991 Feb. (Box 43, Folder 6)
  - Media advisories, 1991 Mar. (Box 43, Folder 7)
  - Media advisories, 1991 Apr. (Box 43, Folder 8)
  - Media advisories, 1991 May. (Box 43, Folder 9)
  - Media advisories, 1991 June. (Box 44, Folder 1)
  - Media advisories, 1991 July. (Box 44, Folder 2)
  - Media advisories, 1991 Aug. (Box 44, Folder 3)
  - Media advisories, 1991 Sept. (Box 44, Folder 4)
  - Media advisories, 1991 Oct. (Box 44, Folder 5)
  - Media advisories, 1991 Nov. (Box 44, Folder 6)
  - Media advisories, 1991 Dec. (Box 44, Folder 7)
  - Media advisories, 1992 Jan. (Box 44, Folder 8)
  - Media advisories, 1992 Feb. (Box 45, Folder 1)
  - Media advisories, 1992 Mar. (Box 45, Folder 2)
  - Media advisories, 1992 Apr. (Box 45, Folder 3)
  - Media advisories, 1992 May. (Box 45, Folder 4)
  - Media advisories, 1992 June. (Box 45, Folder 5)
  - Media advisories, 1992 July. (Box 45, Folder 6)
  - Media advisories, 1992 Aug. (Box 45, Folder 7)
  - Media advisories, 1992 Sept. (Box 45, Folder 8)
  - Media advisories, 1992 Oct. (Box 45, Folder 9)
  - Media advisories, 1992 Nov. (Box 46, Folder 1)
  - Media advisories, 1992 Dec. (Box 46, Folder 2)
  - Media advisories, 1993 Jan. (Box 46, Folder 3)
  - Media advisories, 1993 Feb. (Box 46, Folder 4)
  - Media advisories, 1993 Mar. (Box 46, Folder 5)
  - Media advisories, 1993 Apr. (Box 46, Folder 6)
  - Media advisories, 1993 May. (Box 46, Folder 7)
  - Media advisories, 1993 June. (Box 46, Folder 8)
  - Media advisories, 1993 July. (Box 46, Folder 9)
  - Media advisories, 1993 Aug. (Box 46, Folder 10)
  - Media advisories, 1993 Sept 1-16. (Box 46, Folder 11)
  - Media advisories, 1993 Sept 17-30. (Box 47, Folder 1)
  - Media advisories, 1993 Oct. (Box 47, Folder 2)
  - Media advisories, 1993 Nov. (Box 47, Folder 3)
  - Media advisories, 1993 Dec. (Box 47, Folder 4)
  - Media advisories, 1994 Jan. (Box 47, Folder 5)
  - Press releases - Virginians for the Stadium, 1992 Sept-Oct. (Box 47, Folder 6)
  - Media advisories / Press Release Index, 1989-1992. (Box 47, Folder 7)
- Series III. Governor's Public Schedule, 1990-1993 (Acc. 35539)., Extent: .35 cubic feet (1 box). (Box 48)
  Governor's Public Schedule, 1990-1993, is housed in 1 box and is arranged chronologically. These weekly schedules provide a listing of the Governor's public activities and attendance or appearance at events, such as conferences, meetings, receptions and interviews. Schedule includes the date, time, event, location, and the Governor's role in the event (interview, remarks, address, sign documents, dedication, attend, speech, photo op, etc.).
  - Governor's public schedule, 1990 Jan-June. (Box 48, Folder 1)
  - Governor's public schedule, 1990 July-Dec. (Box 48, Folder 2)
  - Governor's public schedule, 1991 Jan-June. (Box 48, Folder 3)
  - Governor's public schedule, 1991 July-Dec. (Box 48, Folder 4)
  - Governor's public schedule, 1992 Jan-July. (Box 48, Folder 5)
  - Governor's public schedule, 1992 July-Dec. (Box 48, Folder 6)
  - Governor's public schedule, 1993 Jan-July. (Box 48, Folder 7)
  - Governor's public schedule, 1993 July-Dec. (Box 48, Folder 8)
- Series IV. Media Packets, 1991 Oct-1992 July (Acc. 35581)., Extent: .35 cubic feet (1 box). (Box 49)
  Media Packets, 1991 Oct-1992 July, are housed in 1 box and are arranged chronologically. These media packets include weekly public schedules distributed to media outlets with accompanying material such as media advisories, exerpts of remarks and news articles.
  - Media packets, 1991 Oct. (Box 49, Folder 1)
  - Media packets, 1991 Nov. (Box 49, Folder 2)
  - Media packets, 1991 Dec. (Box 49, Folder 3)
  - Media packets, 1992 Jan. (Box 49, Folder 4)
  - Media packets, 1992 Feb. (Box 49, Folder 5)
  - Media packets, 1992 Mar. (Box 49, Folder 6)
  - Media packets, 1992 Apr. (Box 49, Folder 7)
  - Media packets, 1992 May. (Box 49, Folder 8)
  - Media packets, 1992 June. (Box 49, Folder 9)
  - Media packets, 1992 July. (Box 49, Folder 10)
- Series V. Trade Mission Briefing Binders, 1991 (Acc. 35586)., Extent: .7 cubic feet (2 boxes). (Box 1-2)
  Trade Mission Briefing Binders, 1991, are housed in 2 boxes. These binders document trade missions to both Europe (1991 June) and Asia (1991 October). The European Trade Mission traveled to Belgium, Great Britain, Germany and Poland; and the Asian Trade Mission traveled to Hong Kong, Japan and Korea. The briefing binders include scheduling information (events, participants, travel logistics), prelimary information (overview of mission and country), background information for meetings (participants and issues), and general background information (new articles, business reports, companies in Virginia, overview of trade and investment in Virginia).
  - European Trade Mission, 1991 June.
    - Belgium (Brussels), 1991 June. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Great Britain (London), 1991 June. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Germany (Bonn, Frankfurt, Hamburg), 1991 June. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Poland (Warsaw), 1991 June. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Asian Trade Mission, 1991 Oct.
    - Hong Kong, 1991 Oct. (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Japan (Tokyo), 1991 Oct. (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Korea (Seoul), 1991 Oct. (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Series VI. Newspaper articles about Governor Wilder, 1990-1993 (Acc. 35539)., Extent: .35 cubic feet (1 box). (Box 50)
  Newspaper articles about Gov. Wilder, 1990-1993, are housed in 1 box and are arranged chronologically. This series consists of photocopies of newspaper articles about Gov. Wilder.
  - Newspaper articles, 1990. (Box 50, Folder 1)
  - Newspaper articles, 1991. (Box 50, Folder 2)
  - Newspaper articles, 1993. (Box 50, Folder 3)
  - Newspaper articles, undated. (Box 50, Folder 4)
  - Bibliography articles, 1990-1992. (Box 50, Folder 5)
- Series VII. Publications featuring Governor Wilder, 1990-1993 (Acc. 35539)., Extent: 1.75 cubic feet (5 boxes). (Box 50-54)